Kellie Petersen

Front End Developer

JavaScript & React developer with 3 years of experience developing web apps. Proficient in a range of front-end technologies with knowledge in Express & MongoDB. Prioritises creating high-performing, functional and accessible web apps. Genuinely passionate and always self-improving.

Brisbane QLD

hello@kelliepetersen.com www.kelliepetersen.com www.linkedin.com/in/kelliepetersen www.github.com/kelliepetersen

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer / Parchot LLC

Mar 2020 - Dec 2020, Claymont DE, USA (Remote)

- Involved in planning, front-end development, and launch.
- Developed business website using a variety of tools and frameworks when suitable, including React, Gatsby, TypeScript, SASS, Express, and PHP.
- Worked in a team environment following a SCRUM methodology.

Freelance Developer

Jun 2018 - Jan 2020, Atlanta GA, USA

- Designed and developed websites for small businesses.
- Debugged, optimized, and rebuilt outdated websites resulting in 500% faster page load and longer user engagement.
- Collaborated with designers to translate wireframes and mockups into real websites.
- Networked with people in the community and took the time to understand the needs and goals of clients.

SKILLS

JavaScript

TypeScript

React

GatsbyJS & NextJS

Node & Express

MongoDB

npm, Gulp & Webpack

Testing (Jest)

Version Control (Git)

CSS Frameworks (incl. Material UI, Semantic UI, Bootstrap, SASS)

CSS-in-JS (styled-components)

PROJECTS

Rhyton (Ongoing Project)

- Developed the front-end of a financial monitoring app that allows users to pin comments and predictions on stock charts in real-time.
- Built the app in Next.js to benefit from the in-built support for hybrid apps, which are a mix of static and dynamic web pages.
- Designed a modern user experience using Material UI.
- Implemented diagramming of financial data using the D3.js library.

JobLink

- Developed the front-end for an aggregated job searching application that searches job listings by keywords, and compares the frequency different keywords are mentioned on a chart.
- Designed and implemented an interface that was simple to use.
- Mapped fetched data on a bar chart using the Chart.js library.

EDUCATION

Central Queensland University

Bachelor of Laws & Accounting

2012-2017, Rockhampton QLD

Graduated with Distinctions. Formed strong skills in writing, self-learning, researching, analytical problem solving, and teamwork.

Central Queensland University

Honours in Laws

2017, Rockhampton QLD

VOLUNTEER

General / Committee Member

2019 -2021, Carrollton, GA & Brisbane QLD

 Over 100 hours of community outreach providing general assistance and web development services.